Good morning and happy Friday. You're
watching Drogram with Ted R and John
Kuryaku as John and I brace for the big
snowstorm.
>> Seriously, man.
>> I did I tell you night before last my
son and I went to Home Depot. Well, I I
can't find my scraper for my windshield.
Oh, I always lose those.
>> I must have like five of them.
Seriously?
>> Yeah, they're probably buried in the
back recesses of your trunk under
>> They probably are. So So we went to uh
to Target and Target the the shelves
were literally bare. It was like it was
like CO all over again. So it's just
diagonally from across the street from
the Home Depot. So we went there and
mind you, this is this is like 9:00 on a
Wednesday night. We couldn't find a
parking space at the Home Depot, first
of all.
>> So, we had to park where they have sort
of taken the parking spaces and they use
it for storage. You know how Home Depots
do.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we went in and there's a guy holding
a container of of salt, rock salt. And I
said, "Excuse me, can you tell me where
you got the salt?" He said, "Very back
of aisle four, and you better get back
there fast."
We were like, "What?" So, we ran back
there. It's a mob of people. And as
quickly as this poor hapless like
70year-old stock clerk is pulling the
salt out of the boxes, people are just
grabbing them out of his hand. So, I got
three containers, three eight pound
containers, and they're in my trunk. I
gave my son one. I'm going to give a
friend of mine one, and I've got one for
my car just in case. But, man, and the
models are different. And I mentioned
yesterday they haven't changed, at least
this morning when I first woke up, they
hadn't changed, but it was um the
American model and the American AI model
are saying um 8 to 12 in for us, but
then the European model
is saying um uh 20 21 to 26 in here. Let
me look right now. Uh yeah, we're
looking now at at 8 to 10 according to
>> Do we know which which one do you happen
to know which one tends to be more
accurate?
>> I remember downloading this one because
the other one was inaccurate. So I'm
going to say 8 to 10 8 to 12 and we'll
be
>> I swear by Acue weather. It's my it's my
favorite weather app.
>> Yeah. Um you know I like I mean it's
it's almost unearly where this is the
weather channel. They'll say like, you
know, snow stops in 17 minutes and then
it does. Yeah.
>> Okay. I'm going to I'm going to download
it right now.
>> So, I think we're expecting over a foot
um I guess 1 foot and 4 in in New York
City and more in the surrounding areas.
And it's going to be coupled with ice
and severe cold temperatures. Um you
know, it's going to be wind chills
tonight below zero in New York City. uh
and actual temperatures of like single
digits in New York City. Like over the
weekend,
>> we have um uh low of 17, high of 18.
>> Well, at least you know what the
temperature is going to be. It's not one
of those like, oh, like California, like
we need layers. No, not not so much. Um
well, it's gonna it's uh it's cold in
Gaza, but Jared Kushner thinks it's
going to be hotter. We'll we'll talk
about that. Uh and how exactly this is
going to look. You mentioned this
yesterday and I did a deeper dive over
overnight into Jared Kushner's vision
for Club Med Gaza. Uh Minneapolis it is.
I didn't know this was coming. This kind
of snuck up on me.
>> It snuck up on me, too. I actually
didn't know it was coming.
>> There's a citywide strike. Um hundreds
of businesses are going to close down
today. Um thousands, maybe tens of
thousands of Minneapolis, is that what
you call them? I don't know what you
call them. Um are going to be uh are not
are going to refuse to work today. Um,
ICE is already complaining that they
can't get hotel rooms. Their hotel room
reservations get cancelled. Uh, their
uh, you know, they can't get a cup of
coffee. They're refused service. Um, oh,
sad. It's sad to be a, you know,
sadistic
macho steroided [__] Um, and, uh,
Trump is turning to the left. We already
kind of knew this like two weeks ago
when he was talking to Elizabeth Warren,
but he's looking to the left uh, on the
economy. I have thoughts about that. Um,
and the Department of Homeland Security
kind of pulled like what Time magazine
did to OJ Simpson when they darkened his
picture for the cover. Uh, they this one
of the three women who were uh who were
arrested for um being in a protest
against an ICE preacher that those are
the two words I thought I'd go that
would go there.
>> Um,
>> is uh that one of them they uh they
tweeted out her picture. It was modified
by AI to make it look like he was crying
and blacker than she is.
>> Right.
>> So, um, all beautiful stuff. And of
course, obviously, please like, follow,
share the show. Um, we appreciate your
donations as always. We're I think it's
fair to say, John, we're we're now
actually, you know, we can see the light
at the end of the tunnel and it doesn't
seem to be a train heading to run us
over.
>> Amen. The show is doing well now. And
>> yeah, and thanks to everybody.
>> Yes. Yes. Thanks to everybody because
when we first started this, remember we
started it with Michelle
um and uh and I think we had five people
watched the first episode literally.
Quite literally.
>> That's right.
>> And u
>> and we appreciate those five people.
>> We do very much because we it was it was
from that that we grew and uh and now
we're able to, you know, actually pay
the electric bill
>> which was a concern for a while.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. No, for sure. And we have
questions uh in the feeds. So, you know,
maybe we could do what we did yesterday,
John, and knock out knock out a story or
two and then get to the questions. What
do you think?
>> That sounds like a plan.
>> All right. I I'm I'm interested in all
of these things, but you you you get to
pick.
Okay. Um
let's talk about Minneapolis. I I was
invited to a dinner last night uh with
Ilhan Omar. there were about 20 of us
and she talked about this uh this really
what amounts to a general strike in
Minneapolis today and she said something
that I thought was important. Um well
she said a couple of things that I
thought were important that the
administration has underestimated the
resolve of motans
repeatedly and she also said
>> these are sturdy people. It's routinely
20 below zero there. She that was an
important point that she made that these
these ice people from DC or from where
they wherever they are Texas or
California they're they're not used to
Minnesota winters and this is going to
get very old for them very quickly and
um you know to use a line from the
Sopranos from the Pine Barons uh episode
wash their balls with snow. So motans
aren't afraid of these uh of these ice
people in this weather number one.
Number two,
um
motans see this as a legit attack,
a federal attack on their city and state
and they're not going to roll over for
it. So, this is going to get worse
before it gets better. She said that
that the federal government thought
people were just going to roll over.
They were going to run from the
screaming from the room, uh hide in
their homes. That's not it at all. She
said that there are thousands of people
who are at least temporarily hiding
people in their homes so that they can't
be found.
>> Taking a which is taking a risk. Um
that's a felony.
>> It's a felony.
>> God bless them.
>> A fiveyear sentence. God bless them. Is
right. You know, I've said many times
many members of my family came here as
what people call illegal immigrants. and
all they ever wanted to do was to make
money to to care for their families.
They were very happy to pay taxes. They
didn't come in legally as Robbie would
complain u because that option was not
open to them,
>> right?
>> They couldn't come here legally. The
answer was no. We're not giving visas to
Greeks in the postw World War II era.
No. And so, you know, I think that uh
she made a couple of good points last
night that that the administration isn't
really paying much attention to.
>> Um yeah, you know, it's I think it's
always interesting um you get into
trouble politically when you grind up
against um a local indigenous culture.
Um, I was thinking about, uh, you know,
Chris Christie was a really unpopular
governor of New Jersey and he pulled a
lot of [__] as governor, but but what
did him in um, ultimately was two
things, right? Once, one was [__]
with something near and dear to New
Jerseyians, which is their ability to
commute in and out of New York City.
>> Um, that's why he did.
>> Yes. And and so he did a bridgegate
closing the George Washington
effectively closing the George
Washington Bridge. By the way, a lady
died in an ambulance ambulance uh you
know on that day.
>> That's right.
>> And then worst of all in the middle of a
heat wave um closing all the beaches but
going to the beach himself with his
family. Again, New Jersey has a lot of
beach communities and people really
value their, you know, they're like, we
might not live in a in a state that has
its own TV station, but we live in a
state that has beautiful beaches and all
of us are no one's more than an hour or
an hour and 15 minutes away from a
beach. Um, and he's taking that away
from us and he's using it for himself.
[__] you. And this is similar. I mean,
Minne Minneapolis and Motans, you know,
we've all heard the term Minnesota nice
and it's it's a real thing. These are to
a fault hopelessly polite people. You
know, they're Scandinavian uh ethnically
most of the whites are and and that's
the culture that sort of you know,
everybody who moves there kind of has to
adapt to uh regardless of their own
ethnic background. They're and and they
really and you know how it is like New
Yorkers don't care if you're a little
gruff but like you know motans if you're
if you're like that you know if you're
rude and crude people hate you and um
and and that's the exact impression that
ICE made um they culturally could not
have asked for a a worst more grading
crash
say
>> seriously I couldn't agree more Um,
that's why I think this is going to be a
bigger deal than the government realizes
and it's not like, you know, they're
planning to pull out on Tuesday. This is
an ongoing thing.
>> JD Vance kind of um, you know, kind of
uh, you know, tipped, you know, he's a
smart guy. He can, you know, he takes
the temperature. He knows what's up. And
he said, you know, we want to turn down
the temperature. Well, that's a new
statement from the administration.
They've been turning up the temperature
all the way to like 600. And now um you
know but the thing is they're not doing
the things that are required to to turn
down the temperature. Just saying you
want to turn it down doesn't do
anything. Um I guess this brings up the
issue of the uh of the Homeland Security
uh Twitter account. I mean, which by the
way is a cesspool of like um you know,
alt-right uh you know, wink wink nod nod
to like neo-Nazism
um and you know, sort of crazy like
memes that look like they come out, you
know, Norman Rockwellish kind of 1930s
like you know, not that he Norman
Rockwell was a right-winger, far from
it, but that kind of idealized all-white
American vision. Um but anyway, they
they they tweeted out a picture altered
of uh one of the three women who um they
arrested at uh for disturbing the peace,
I guess, basically. I think they're all
going to walk. No question. Um you know,
for basically yelling at this ICE
preacher for being of ICE uh during a
church service, right? I mean, there's I
can't see what where the where the law
breaking is here unless you can't charge
someone with trespassing. Listen, I've
become a a YouTube expert on this kind
of thing. You can't charge someone with
the crime of trespassing until you have
trespassed them, which means you have to
give them written notification that they
are not permitted on your property.
Somebody, you can't just arrest somebody
and charge them with trespassing because
they walk into a church and start
yelling.
>> Yes.
>> The vampire law rule where I uninvite
you and they fly out the door. Exactly.
Exactly.
>> Um, yeah. No, so so the so this woman,
right, I mean, first of all, even if
they had tweeted out her photograph, I
mean, this is an agency that complains
about federal employees, ICE officers
being doxed, right, by by leftist
activists. Here they are doxing a uh,
you know, a private citizen, right? A
uh, a person of color, a woman on top of
it. So that would make that makes me
really uncomfortable. But on top of
that, they altered the image to look at
make it look like she was in tears. She
wasn't.
>> She wasn't.
>> And um you know, she was brave and
composed and um she and they made her uh
they they changed the color of her skin.
They tinted her to make her look more to
make her look darker.
>> Um this is racist. It's a racist. It's a
racist thing to do.
>> Just racist.
>> The Christy Gnome ow owes her and the
country an apology.
>> Yeah. Couldn't agree more.
>> And this is not turning down the
remember? Of of course you remember the
[__] that Time magazine took when they
darkened OJ Simpson's
uh booking uh picture, his his mug shot.
>> Yeah,
>> they had to make an apology and they
said that it was, you know, it was a
poorly thoughtout attempt to make it
look more stark. And yeah,
>> I actually knew the editor who approved
that image at Time magazine because I
was doing cartoons there at at the time
>> and it did turn out to be kind of a
production [__] Um, and which you
know people people don't know like when
you produce something in a magazine like
they you have to create what they call a
match print. You're not really sure what
it's going to look like until it rolls
off the press. Um, and you you kind of
need to print. So anyway, apparently
they were late that day because of the
OJ story. So they didn't have time to do
a match proof. And then the thing, it's
actually a fascinating story. It's sort
of like the uh the Dean scream. I knew
someone who was working at his campaign.
>> The mic was malfunctioning that night.
And when Howard Dean was like, you know,
shouting or trying to get he was trying
Yeah. He was trying to make his mic work
and it kind of played into this awkward
kind of uh you know image that the that
the corporate media was trying to to
paint of him.
>> I I always liked him.
>> Oh, I'm a big fan. And the 50 state the
50 state um
>> uh strategy is the way to go for any
party.
>> Absolutely. Oh my god. See, the Clintons
did this to the Democratic party because
it was James Carville who insisted on a
50-st state uh strategy. Mhm.
>> This is something, this is not a new
idea. This is something that George
McGovern proposed in 1960
when he first ran for the Senate. Um,
and that's why the Democrats were able
to elect senators from North and South
Dakota, from Wyoming, from Oklahoma,
from Utah. I mean, there were Democratic
senators.
>> You don't write off entire sections of
the country.
>> No. And what the Clintons did was they
ended financing for Democratic
candidates at the state representative
level.
>> Mhm.
>> Which controls redistricting in
>> and also it killed their farm system.
Right. Somewhere somewhere in some state
house there's a there's some lady who
could be the president of the United
States in 40 years. But you know, you
don't we don't know that because Yeah.
because she's not going to get any
money. She'll be defeated by a
Republican. Um, yeah. No, it's it's
really boneheaded for a variety of
reasons. We could do an entire show on
that. All right, let me see um about
getting into So, Robbie is just getting
uh just getting to us. So, I'm going to
please bear with me, guys, while I uh
parse through the comments here. Much
appreciated. Um K dot, I'm gonna sort of
work through these u on YouTube. Uh Ted,
you mentioned how one day you'd like a
good documentarian to tell your story
one day. The first name and channel that
came to mind when I heard that was
Andrew from channel 5 news. Uh, okay.
Um, I don't know who that is, but sick.
Um, if anyone wants to contact me, it's
raw.comcont.
Um, Nicholas Franco, John, can you
explain a little bit about the situation
with the stateless people in Kuwait?
When I was studying for my bachelor's
degree, I met two girls. They said
they're refugees from Kuwait.
>> Kuwaiti citizenship is a difficult
thing. Um there are multiple levels of
Kuwaiti citizenship. Three. There are
first class Kuwaitis,
second class and third class. Now a
first class Kuwaiti is a descendant of
someone who can trace his Kuwaiti
citizenship to the census of 1920.
Right? So they had this big census in
1920. If you want to be Kuwaiti, come
and sign up. Well, a lot of people
didn't bother because they were like,
what is this state? this we're better
ones. Everything is our state. We just
move from place to place.
>> This was created by the by the by the
treaty of Versailles.
>> No, it coincided with the Treaty of
Versailles.
>> Okay.
>> Secondass Kuwaitis are descendants of
people who can trace their lineage to
people who were in Kuwait in 1920 but
didn't register.
Okay. Okay. Third class Kuwaitis are
people who have been granted Kuwaiti
citizenship for whatever reason. You
served the royal the ruling family. You
did some special thing but who do not
have the privileges of first and
secondass citizenship. And then there
are stateless people called bedun. Bedun
uh in Arabic means without. So they are
without papers without citizenship.
That's not the same word as bedawin.
>> No, it comes from the same route to
move. Badana, to move around.
>> So bedawins kind of go through the
desert, Kuwait, Saudi Arabia, Iraq.
They're constantly nomads. They're
moving from oasis to oasis with their
flocks.
>> But the bedun
tend to, you know, live in Kuwait City
like everybody else does. They just
don't have a passport. They don't have
any rights. They have to travel on
United Nations issued LZ pes. And so
like uh like these two girls apparently
um you get a laz p that allows you to to
travel to the United States to go to
school, but you are not a Kuwaiti
citizen.
>> Huh. Okay.
>> It's rough.
>> All right. Sneaker dad 10 uh 20. Thanks
for the 10 bucks and thank um very much
much appreciated. Um did you see Vance's
talk yesterday? So much us versus them.
Katie catastrophe red versus blue. It
was sickening. Sickening. Well, that's
it is sickening. I you know I mean very
clearly this administration repeatedly,
you know, says the quiet part out loud,
which is if you're not a Republican and
you're not a supporter of President
Trump, we don't care about you. Um we
don't care if you live or die. Um I
guess the question for me, and I don't
know, I really don't know the answer to
this. Does this make Republicans or
Trump supporters uncomfortable or do
they love it?
>> That's a good question.
That's a good question. I I don't know.
But you know what though? Even if it did
make them uncomfortable, they would
remain silent. We're not yet at a at a
point. We're starting to get to this
point in the Senate, but we're not yet
at a point where people are comfortable
enough criticizing Donald Trump. once we
get past the next election in November
and Trump truly is a lame duck because
he's not running for a third term. I
don't care what he says. Um then I think
people will feel much more comfortable
in um criticizing him. Hey, let me add
one other thing. Um Elanar mentioned
last night at this dinner that she had
just come from a series of budget votes
on Capitol Hill. We got we were getting
push notifications last night. So what
the Democrats did because there are
utter and complete and total sellouts
um is they um they demanded that the
budget for Department of Homeland
Security be stripped out of the omnibus.
So she called it a minibus which I had
never heard before. It was kind of
funny. So
>> all the Yeah. All the Democrats voted
for the minibus which funded the the
entire government except Homeland
Security, but the Republicans were
unified on the Homeland Security vote
last night. And there were just enough
by like by like a majority of two or
three that they approved the Homeland
Security uh budget, which includes ICE,
of course. Of course. and she and she
said that the only hope that the
Democrats have to either block the DHS
budget or to shut down the government
again is on the Senate side. She said
the Republicans are nowhere near 60
votes necessary to break closure. So I
said, "Are you predicting a government
shutdown brought by the Democrats?" and
she said,"Not necessarily." She said,
"Because many of my Democratic
colleagues on the second side are
sellouts and weaklings."
So, we'll see what happens. Nobody's
reporting this yet that there is a a
real possibility of another government
shutdown. Uh, when? March something.
>> I would love to see some [__]
discipline inside the Democratic caucus.
>> It's chaos. It's chaos. where where Jeff
was basically like, I will kick your ass
so far down the street if you stray from
our party's official position, you won't
even [__] remember. Um, but yeah,
that's we're not there obviously and
it's not going to happen. Good question
for you, John. I'm curious about this.
Yeah. For a Vita, John, if an ex-source
ever an ex source ever hit you up asking
to meet up and talk about life, would
you follow up or the curiosity not worth
the risk or is it simply just not
allowed?
I absolutely would. I actually have
>> ah
>> uh on two occasions.
One time I ran into one of my sources,
an Iraqi in Dulles airport here in
Washington. He says to me, "John, John,
like that." And I looked and I go, I go,
"Muhammad,
what are you doing here?" He said, "I
became a refugee and now I'm an American
citizen." I was like, "Oh my god." We
sat and had coffee and it dawned on me
partway through the conversation. I
said, "Wait a minute, you're speaking
English."
And he's like, "Yeah, I learned how to
speak English." It just it didn't
register in my brain that
>> when you see someone out of context, I
guess it's a more extreme version of
like when I see my dry cleaning dude at
like the bar
>> and I'm like, "Right, wait, you live at
the dry cleaner? I don't understand."
>> Exactly. Oh my god. I was at I was at
the Town Mall in Newcastle, Pennsylvania
one time with my mom. I was 16 and there
was this uh
>> We're not allowed to use the word [__]
anymore. What do we say?
>> Short person. Little person.
>> There was a a little person. Yes.
>> And uh we're walking down the, you know,
middle of the mall and he goes, "Hey,
how you doing?" I said, "Hey, how are
you?" And my mom goes, "How in the world
do you know that guy?" And I said, "Oh,
I he must have confused me with somebody
else." The truth is that he was the
bartender at the bar that served minors
that my buddies and I used to go buy
six-packs
>> at City Lights Cafe. Anyway, God bless
those people. I I remember when I my
first day at college, um 1981 in New
York, the drinking age was 18 at at
Columbia. I cidle up to the bar and
there's like three like girls from like
New Jersey drinking and they're all like
they couldn't none of them could have
been older than 12. So I I would the
bartender was flirting with me and she's
like 40 and uh and and I go, "What's up
with the uh you know what about what's
with these ladies?" And she goes, "I
know you're new you're new to New York
City." She's like, "If you're old enough
to pay, you're old enough to drink."
>> City Lights Cafe, man. and and
occasionally Hanging Gardens uh bar and
lounge. Hanging Gardens was good, but
there was a bartender there that that
knew my parents, so I tried to stay
away.
>> And in where I grew up, we had the best
names for bars that like had plausible
deniability.
>> Nowhere. Hey, where have you been?
>> Nowhere.
>> Um the library.
>> There was a whole row of bars like that
on Dixie Highway in Ketaring, Ohio.
>> Oh my god. Anyway, so let's see. Uh,
John, you've mentioned on several
podcasts, this is from KOT, that you
like to visit cemeteries a lot during
your spare time as part of your writing
process. Have you ever had a paranormal
or ghost encounter while there?
>> No, that's a fun question.
>> That's a very
>> No, I I never have. I I I was walking
through uh Columbia Garden Cemetery here
near my house um one one night. It was
nighttime, like legit dark, but I mean,
there's no reason to be afraid at night
in a cemetery. And I heard this
screaming
that scared the [__] out of me. And it
turned out that there's a den of foxes
that lives in the uh that lives in the
uh cemetery. And they were fighting.
That's all it was. But no, I've never
had a paranormal experience in the
cemetery.
>> Foxes make Foxes are Foxes are so cool.
I love them.
>> No, we have so many of them around here.
And they like walk right up to you.
They're not afraid or anything. And they
eat the rabbits.
>> We have both.
>> Okay.
>> Most mostly red. I see mostly red ones.
>> Thanks for the two bucks on Sung Pat.
Um, okay. Uh, Angela Fala Laala. I'm
sure I think this is for you. I'm pretty
sure this for you, John. Thanks for the
Fiverr. Um, have you ever met Evie P?
Uh, uh, Pumpuros.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Former Secret Service now all over
YouTube and Greek like you. Obviously.
>> I've seen her in church a couple of
times. Uh she's she's quite good. She's
very very bright. She was a Secret
Service agent for I don't know 12 15
years. Um
I remember she took a lot of [__] from
the the male Secret Service agents. They
were real jerks to her. She left to
become an author and a journalist. And
her book was quite wellreceived. It was
kind of a combination memoir
um self-help book. I don't remember the
name of it, but but it was quite
wellreceived and now she's out on the
speaking circuit all the time and she's
she's she's done well for herself.
>> Uh, another one for you, John Alfred
Bucks. Thank you very much. Um, Joby
Warwick is releasing the the Jackal. I
know we've talked about that here
before. Were you a reference for the
book and would you consider having him
on Deadrop it?
>> Uh, yeah. I I was a reference for the
book. He and I talked about it as
recently as I don't know six or eight
months ago. And it it's funny. I've
known Joby for years. He's a he's a
brilliant journalist and a multiple
Pulitzer Prize winner. Serious like deep
investigative journalist who somehow
finds the time to bang out number one
New York Times bestselling books in his
spare time. I don't know how he does it.
>> Research assistant is helpful.
>> Yeah, a good one. Yeah,
>> a good one. Um, and uh, yeah, he called
me and he said that a friend of his said
that I had been teaching this class at
the University of Salamanca and that I
was spending a lot of time talking about
Carlos the Jackal. And I said, "Yeah,
yeah, I I have." And um, and he said,
"Well, I'm I'm doing this book. Would
you would you talk to me about it?" I
said, "Absolutely." So, we had uh
coffee. We spent a couple of hours
talking about Carlos the Jackal. And
then he came out with his book. He's
doing well for himself, too. Good old
Joby.
Robbie, do we have an ad?
>> Hey, there's Robbie.
>> No. Okay.
I just thought that would be a funny way
to do it. Um, okay. So, uh, okay. So,
uh,
um, Fasmataz says, "Target shelves empty
near DC. How's the Pentagon gay bar and
pizza index looking? My money is on a
strike against Iran tonight."
Unfortunately, it would be a good with
the weather
>> and all the distraction going, this
would there would be this would be a
good uh great weekend for a media dump.
>> Yeah, you could say that again. Um Ryan
Grim was at this dinner last night. Uh
Ryan is from Deadrop Media. Very, very
well connected. and um somehow we got on
to the topic of of Iran. And um he said
he does not expect an attack on Iran in
the next week or two, but all bets are
off once this carrier battle group, the
USS Abraham Lincoln, finally gets to the
region. He said he he does believe that
we're looking at an attack on Iran in
the coming months. Yes,
>> I would agree with that. Um Karak,
thanks for the 10 bucks. And I John,
this question is for you, but I would
like to chime in on it as well. What are
your rules for accepting uh Arab
hospitality? I'm not sure every random
taxi driver and shopkeeper actually
wants to host me for tea at their home,
but I'm curious. I think they actually
do, but go ahead.
>> They do actually. And and I'll tell you
the honest to God's truth is I never say
no. Never. Hey, I'll tell you the first
time this happened. It's rude to have a
shitty reputation as it is.
>> Yes. It's it's quite bad form to say no.
The first time this ever happened to me
was I was in Damascus in 199 I don't
know two or three. I it was my first
trip to Syria and my boss had told me
beforehand he said Syrians are so
insular and so afraid of their
government that you will never meet a
nonofficial Syrian and you will never
see the inside of a Syrian's home. So I
went to the souk
and um
and this guy asked me Wayne, "Where are
you from?" And I said,
"From the United States." And he just
looked at me like, and I said, "You've
never met an American, have you?" And he
said, "No, I've never met an American."
So we stood there talking. I bought a
tablecloth that I think my ex-wife stole
from me in our divorce. And um he said,
"You have to come to my home. you have
to come to my home for dinner. And I
said, "Oh, no, no, no, no. I don't want
to, you know, make a problem for you."
Which could have been a serious problem
for him. He insisted and then he picked
up the phone, called his wife, closed
the shop around 9:00. We went to his
house and I still remember what a
wonderful time I had at that dinner. You
know, even recently I was in when was I
in Jerusalem? In like in 2022
um and um and a taxi driver invited me
to his house for dinner and dropped
dropped me off at uh at my hotel, picked
me up three hours later and took me to
his house for dinner just in time for me
to buy, you know, some flowers for his
wife and you know, whatever. But I never
say no because they mean it when they
invite you. They mean it. They mean it
and it it's very insulting if you say
no. Like in Japan, they don't mean it um
at all. Don't say don't say yes. If you
accept it, you're you're being an
[__] Uh but like no, in in like um
in in Wadi Rum where they filmed uh
Lawrence of Arabia in Jordan.
>> Yes.
>> Um I had a car accident to the Wadi Rum.
>> I I I had a car accident. It was bad.
The car rolled into the desert. It It
was total I still have the key. Um, and
the, uh, and I went through the
windshield. And so, uh, it was a, it was
a hell of a day. And finally,
>> you went through the windshield.
>> I went through the windshield.
>> Yeah. I had like I had safety glass all
embedded in my in my in my skull. Right.
>> I I didn't know that.
>> So, my uh, this was 2000 year 2000. This
was actually, it's a funny story. You
um, it has a connection to you maybe
obliquely um, to the Millennium plot.
So, I was staying at the Moven Pic with
my wife um in uh on December on New
Year's Eve 1999, December 31st, 1999 in
Y2K. Um the Moven pick is at the
entrance of Petra and uh we you know we
were [__] around Petra for a couple
of days and we did the New Year's
celebration with like the British
ambassador to Jordan and all these
people and um this was be so be later
this accident took place but we later
learned right that that hotel was
targeted to be blown up by al Qaeda and
that night and that uh this operation
that had been disrupted by Jordanian
intelligence Um they they had a list of
like a dozen hotels they were going to
blow up all at the same time. Um I don't
know how far along it got, but anyway,
the point is it was kind of creepy like
feeling a bullet go by, you know, by
your ear or something like Trump can
probably attest. And
>> and uh anyway, the point is rolled the
car in the desert and um this guy
stopped and uh this Bedawin guy stopped
in his Jeep and gave us a ride. Uh he
was like I guess part Bedawin because he
had a house and he insisted that we you
know all I wanted to do was get back to
the hotel, take a bath and and pull the
safety glass out of my scalp. Um but
he's like you have to come to my house.
I'm like literally like okay and my
wife's like what the [__] are you doing?
I'm like we got to we have no choice. We
have to. That's how in that's how
insistent it is for sure.
>> Yeah. This Syrian guy, the only thing he
asked of me was that when I got back to
Washington, if I would send him a
postcard,
which I gladly did. He just wanted to
have a postcard with a scene from
Washington DC.
>> I don't know why Tammy's talking
referencing all the young dudes, but any
reference to Mont the Hoopal I will
take. Famously David Bowie wrote all the
young dudes to save Monta Hoopel.
>> I freaking loved Monta Hoopel. I saw
them at GW in 1982.
>> They're fantastic. And Ian Hunter's solo
career is amazing.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, he's still going strong and his
records are great. I mean, you know,
it's not one of those like nostalgia
things. Like, if you'd never heard of
Ian Hunter and you bought like his most
recent album, you'd be like, "This is a
good rock album."
>> Yeah. Seriously.
>> Uh, okay. So, any insights on Apollo
global management contacts with ICE and
the government? Uh, Apollo acquired
Contelis Holdings, formerly Blackwater.
This is Unsung Pat. Thanks for the 10
bucks.
I I don't know enough to answer the
question to tell you the truth. Have you
followed this?
>> I don't know anything about it. And by
the way, about Minnesota again, right?
Um a little bit yesterday, I talked
about how uh you know, general strike's
not going to work in without a
broad-based left-wing organization. But
like what about I mean I guess the the
part that's a little weird about this is
the people who are going to suffer from
all these closed businesses are going to
be Minneapolis's economy. Yeah.
>> Right. I mean the businesses themselves,
>> which tells you how serious they are
about this.
>> Yeah. But it's almost like when there's
a riot and people burn down their own
neighborhood because they're pissed off
at someone else. Um I mean I don't know.
I mean I'm glad they're doing something.
I mean, this is it seems like it puts
the pressure really on local
politicians, but the local politicians
don't want ice there, and we already
know they don't want ice there. I don't
know what they're supposed to do,
really.
>> Yeah, I agree with you.
>> Three birds, one stone, two bucks.
Thanks very much. Where do where do we
see the world in five years? Honest
thoughts, though, although optimism is
not entirely off the table. That's
hilarious. You can go, John.
I think that in one way or another,
we're going to be in the process of
trying to rebuild our long-standing
international friendships and
relationships.
>> Serious damage has been done. Serious
damage. For example, this morning,
President Trump threw the Canadians off
of the so-called peace board that uh
he's creating for Gaza, like it's his to
create. um threw the Canadians off
because he's angry about the speech that
Prime Minister Carney gave at uh at
Davos.
So, we've got a lot of work to do to try
to repair these relationships.
>> I mean, I think also the the body
politics is has never been more divided.
Um the divisions between left and right,
Democrats, Republicans, uh the total
distrust in the system. I mean, to me,
it's very reminiscent of the stuff I've
read about the late VHimar Republic and
just like the there's just like no faith
whatsoever
>> in uh in the in the uh you know, in
representative democracy. It just feels
like it, you know, nobody thinks they
care about us. Um and that's very toxic.
I mean, I could see the system
collapsing entirely. Although frankly I
hate this system and would love to see
it replaced but um you know I mean the
problem is we don't have something
waiting in the wings to replace it.
That's all you know whatever however
shitty your system is it can always get
worse.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's right. It can always
get worse.
Yeah. Hey, did you happen to see that
that President Trump said the other day
he was talking about US Italian
relations? Did you see this?
>> No, I think I missed it. He was talking
about USI Italian relations and he said
that our relations with Italy have been
excellent since Roman times.
And the and the translator looks at him
like what? And then and then and then
she translates it.
>> It's like I don't know if he knows how
long ago that was. Um
>> it's like George W. Bush with the
Grecians,
>> you know? We we love the Grecians.
>> And the Greeks are like, "What?
>> Jesus Christ." I mean, I Okay, so I know
it's like the equivalent of like a you
know, a pole tax or something, but I
kind of feel like you should have to
pass a basic history and politics test
to be allowed to run for president.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I would agree.
>> Yeah. It would rule out pretty much
almost everyone who ever runs. So,
that's that would have that benefit. Um,
John, have you ever run? Uh, Young
Courthouse wants to know, and thanks for
the buck. Have you ever uh uh crossed
paths with a Jack Lee in the 1990s?
>> No, I'm sorry. I can't say that I have.
>> Uh, okay. Um, the one and only Scars.
Hey, John. I'm in high school and speak
Arabic. Do you recommend trying to join
the CIA?
>> That's a uh longer conversation. I'll
put it this way. If if you are inclined
to join the CIA
>> Mhm. um in order to make changes from
the inside.
Absolutely.
You know, I as much as I criticized the
CIA and Ted and I have talked about this
a million times, I loved every minute of
that career. I went to 72 countries. I
met with kings and presidents and prime
ministers and had the experience of a
lifetime. So if you're inclined to do
that kind that kind of work knowing that
you may have to stand up one day and say
this is wrong and I'm not doing it and
I'm making a a whistleblower complaint
then go for it. The career is
magnificent.
>> Um thank you for gentlemen for your
work. Uh and thank you for the five
Canadian dollars. Um John you must
mentioned the CIA uses a lot of cheap
gadgets from Amazon. Then what's DARPA
for? Ah, DARPA is for the big ticket
items, the the Black Mirror robot dogs,
the the soldiers, the robot soldiers
that that we're developing now that the
only reason they're not on the
battlefield fighting is because we
haven't developed a long life battery
yet. That's what DARPA is for. Stuff
that we haven't even thought of. But if
you want to bug a room or plant a camera
or something, just get it off of Amazon.
Um, John, what's the website you use to
track aircraft carriers that you have
mentioned?
>> Oh, let me see if I can find it again.
>> Uh, Aaron Arnold wants to know, Ted, do
you use a seat belt now?
100%.
By the way, the car that I was driving
didn't have a seat belt. Um, so there is
that.
Okay.
No, that wasn't the one. Oh, here it is.
Got it.
It is. Yes, here it is. So, it's
it's go
www. You know what? Why don't I put it
in the chat?
>> Okay. Do go ahead and do that. Uh,
unsung pat. Wow. Thanks for the 50
bucks. When it comes to the Middle East,
why don't we talk about one, the Lord
Rothschild letter, my family created
Israel. Two, the lies after World War I
that chopped up the Middle East. Three,
the 1948 1950 uh yam uh yam bulk miz
child affair. I don't know the third
one.
>> I don't know the third one. Um I guess
maybe you can uh elaborate on that one
uh Pat, but um you know I I think that
like in America you lose I have lost
every single
historical and political argument that
I've ever made that relied on someone
under either knowing history or
believing that I knew history or
believing that history was relevant to
today. it just doesn't have much effect.
You know, Americans are ahistorical. I
mean, and it's, you know, part of it's a
superpower. We're always looking
forward. We're not wallowing in the
past. You know, we're not pissed off
about the 1389 battle of Kosovo. Um but
we are still um but part of the problem
is you know when you try to say well
this is how we the reason it's important
in my view to know how we got here in
any situation is because then we won't
make the mistake of making the same
mistake in the future and being like
okay uh you know now everything's solved
like if we know for example that a lot
of the [__] that Trump does is stuff
that Obama did and that Biden did and
that Bush did then we know that these
are things that, you know, we we're not
going to think that just electing
Democrats is going to solve the Trump
problem. Um, but like the point is that
most people just they can't relate to it
and not in America. This in France or
any other Greece, any other country, you
can Russia, you can make a historical
argument and it resonates like
incredibly powerfully. But yeah,
>> I don't know how to get around that.
I've just, you know, I've tried it my
entire life. It never ever works and
I've never see it work with anyone else.
Yeah, I think I think you've hit that on
the head. I agree.
>> Um, relaxed garden. John, do you really
think we can repair those relationships
with our allies? I hope we can, but I'm
not sure if they'll take us seriously
anymore.
>> I I do actually. I do. Um,
you know, we repaired our relationships
after George W. Bush, and it can be done
again. Remember that old saying that
there's no such thing as permanent
friendships, just permanent interests.
and our interests are going to continue
to intersect. And so whether we, you
know, have hurt feelings on one side or
both or not,
>> those those relationships will be
repaired.
>> And some foreign leaders will will think
to themselves, well, that was crazy
Trump. It's better now.
>> Right. Exactly.
>> Um, Cat Melvin, I hate the system and
would like love to see your replace.
That's me. Uh, there you go. That's why
we're doomed. Everyone wants some kind
of dramatic showdown. It's bad. I don't
want a dramatic showdown. I just don't
think this system is reformable. Um I
would pref be very clear here. You
should never have a revolution if you
can avoid it. Revolution really sucks.
Um but you know if but there are there
are problems that can only be solved by
revolution.
>> Um Desert Fox 41. What would you
recommend John for a history major with
a polysai minor in their last semester
at Satan Hall? This is very specific
John. uh you know who is 5'9 and 12 147
pounds uh with brown hair. No about what
to do about a career. I am extremely
concerned. Um I don't know what
concerned about
>> Don't be extremely concerned. I know
that you feel like you're under the gun,
but don't feel bad about taking a job
that is going to end up being temporary.
You're young. you have literally a whole
lifetime ahead of you. You know, it took
it took so long for my CIA clearances to
come through. Even though I was sort of,
you know, expedited through the the Old
Boy network, it took 18 months for my my
clearances to come through. And so I had
to take a job at the Office of Personnel
Management doing background
investigations for other people to get
their clearances. That wasn't a career.
I knew it wasn't a career. It was a
bunch of bozos just going through the
the motions of being a pretend cop. And
so, um, so don't be hard on yourself. Go
ahead and take a take a temporary, uh,
job that, you know, is not going to be a
career while you do other things to
improve your your lot in life. Get a get
a graduate degree, a master's degree,
learn a foreign language, uh, develop
another skill. Just give yourself a
little bit of time. Don't worry about
it.
>> Yeah. No. And and also the thing is your
education can end up helping you in
unexpected ways. I have a colleague, a
cartoonist, his name uh he goes by the
name Ruben Bowling. It's not his real
name, but he does a strip called Tom the
Dancing Bug. He went to Harvard Law
School. He's never practiced law. Um and
I'm sure that came as a great
disappointment to his parents. He
graduated at the top of his class. He
would have been an absolutely brilliant
attorney. um you know and certainly he's
like freelanced as like a you know
parallegal but he's never been a lawyer
but his cartoons are infused with that
sort of legalistic um approach and he
draws on legal knowledge for his work.
He's the only cartoonist who can do
that. Um and it shows and it might be
like one of those things like you know
you could read his work your entire life
and never know but the point is it's in
there. It's part of the br the the the
witch's brew that makes for this magic
comic strip. Um you just never know how
you're how how things are going to play
out in terms of how your educ I mean you
know I I I went to engineering school
for three years. I have a physics u I
have a physics minor. I never use it but
still it informs the way I think the you
know sort of the scientific method like
things are you know how I ascertain
whether something is likely to be true
that's very subtle but you know it helps
me in all sorts of other in in my
politics um teflon money don um for both
of us
>> uh for viewers who may not know much
about Lebanon how do you see the country
fitting into the Middle East today?
Well, how I see the country fitting in
the Middle East is going to be vastly
different from how Donald Trump sees the
country fitting in the Middle East
because Donald Trump's view is Israel,
Israel, Israel. And you know, my
position on that. I think that we have
we have very strong relations with, you
know, the the GCC countries, the Saudi
Arabia, Kuwait, Bahrain, Qatar, Oman,
and the United Arab Emirates. Very uh
good relations. I think we could do a
lot to improve our relations with with
Algeria, Tunisia, um even Egypt,
relations with Morocco are very good.
Lebanon's a basket case. We should be
somehow working to to, you know, to
bring the the Lebanese economy back to
life. I'm actually going to give an
interview to to a Lebanese network this
afternoon about that very issue.
>> And location, location, location, right?
Lebanon's Lebanon's jammed up between
Oh, I mean Syria was a bigger power,
right? And um and and it will be again.
>> Yes.
>> But Israel, Turkey, I mean, they're
surrounded by big bruisers who always
push them around.
>> Um on the other hand, location,
location, location, they have a lot of
shoreline, they have ports, they have uh
beautiful beaches. Um you know, there's
potential there. There's inherent value
in Lebanon. I mean, you know, and
>> agreed.
>> I mean, as as a tourist destination, it
could be [__] off the charts.
>> Yeah, without without a doubt. I mean,
speaking of which, so we all remember,
everybody who's watching this show, I
know has seen that AI video that came
out at the height of the Gaza war, um,
of, you know, the Trump Trump Tower,
Gaza, Trump casino, Gaza with the giant
gold Trump statue and, uh, all that
stuff. I used it in the thumbnail today.
Um do you um you know yesterday or two
days ago you mentioned this yesterday
morning Jared Kushner uh I guess this
was yesterday local time at Davos uh
made a presentation that kind of echoed
that leaked um uh uh Israeli document um
that sort of had this vision for Gaza.
It's basically full-fledged
exploitation, right? It's all rubble.
We're going to we're going to build
brand new cities on over the rubble and
over the bodies of the dead
Palestinians. Um we're going to start
from scratch. It's all going to be
glitzy and luxurious and touristy.
John, questions. Who's going to own this
land? How are they going to get and and
how will they get it? Will they will
would the Israelis or the other um you
know western developers who want to
build there would they sort of go with
the Maui model or where they exploit um
the misery and uh and desperation of the
of the property owners to get the song
to get the the land at a for a song and
then build there? Will the Israelis
annex it and just eminent domain it and
steal it? Um, or is this just all
[__] and incapable of happening in
the same way that like the Trans
Afghanistan pipeline project was never
going to happen because it required
going through a war zone. Um, you know,
what's going to happen here?
>> I'm not sure anything is going to happen
here. The you're the first thing that
you said is I think the most important
in that
this is not our call. We don't get to
make these decisions.
We can't just pretend. It's not ours.
And we can't pretend that Palestinians
don't live in Gaza or shouldn't live in
Gaza or won't live in Gaza in the near
future.
>> So this whole this whole think it's a
fantasy.
>> I do. And I think this whole peace board
or peace commission or whatever it is
that Donald Trump is charging people a
billion dollars to be a member of and
then just appoints his friends and
family. Um
I just don't see how this could possibly
carry out a policy. It would be like me
just saying, you know what, uh there's
this island in Papua Newu Guinea. Uh I'm
going to develop it. I'm going to charge
people a billion dollars to be on my
board of directors. I'm going to develop
this island. I don't own it. I've never
been there. Uh but uh but yeah, I'm I'm
going to do this. And then what? You
expect people just to step into line?
I just don't see it happening.
>> Yeah. It does feel like they're high.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> Yeah. I mean, it's also But you know,
and then there's the politics of it,
right? I mean, how are the is how are
the Palestinians and those of us who
care about them supposed to look at
this? Um, you know, basically it's like
we're, you know, you basically want to
build this shiny, glittering Las Vegas
on top of this giant grave, the graves
of hundreds of thousands of dead gazins.
>> Yeah. Um, and you know what of the
people who are suffering horribly there
now that you just don't give a [__]
about?
>> That's right.
>> Exactly right. I couldn't agree more.
>> Um, we sh we should before we do some
more questions. I I really want to get
your thoughts about um I thought it was
interesting that Trump um is reported in
Politico to be looking to the left for
ideas about economic populism. things
like a cap on credit card interest, um
things like coming up with a uh health,
uh you know, impro improvement on
Obamacare, and they're saying, "Oh, he's
looking to the left rather than the
right for a, you know, to in order to
address the affordability crisis." Well,
I mean, famously, liberals like to say
that truth as a liberal bias. I wouldn't
say that's true, but I I will say that
uh econ that um you know caring about
ordinary people economically has a
left-wing bias. Right-wingers don't care
by definition. I've just never seen an
idea come out of the Republican party or
out of the right that addresses issues
like people are poor, they can't pay
their bills, they can't pay their rent.
Um they just don't have ideas for that.
You know, we're still waiting for a a
real health care plan. I mean, this puts
this puts lefties into an awkward
position, though, right? Like, if
Elizabeth Warren works with Trump and he
ends up selling one of her ideas and and
she gets the satisfaction of seeing her
idea become come to fruition, but she's
also empowered Donald Trump and maybe
improved his chances in the midterms.
>> What do you do in a situation like that?
>> What do you do? Yeah.
I mean, I I mean, personally, I say you,
if it were me, I'd say, you know, you
take you take your you you take your
wins where you can get them.
>> Yeah, that's kind of my standing
position.
Yeah, I'm happy to form alliances
wherever I can and uh and take my wins.
>> Thanks for the 10 bucks, Waterways. Much
appreciated. Uh much much. Um, how hard
is it to learn? Desert Fox wants to
know, "How's it hard to learn Lebanese
Arabic?"
>> Oh, it's actually not that hard. I mean,
once you have a foundation in standard
Arabic,
many of the uh many of the films that
are made that are broadcast all around
the Middle East are in Lebanese or
Syrian dialect and so everybody in the
Middle East has
an acquaintance with them.
>> Psychonaut.
Good name. John, was there any time in
the past that the CIA used the company
as a reference to the agency or is that
just from the movies?
>> Never. Ever. Ever. These days,
>> never.
If anybody ever said to me that they
worked for the company, I'd say, "Get
the [__] out of here, you phony."
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. No, that's just in the movies.
Literally, no one ever in my life ever
mentioned company.
>> Right. Is that the That's the name of a
famous book, right? Inside the company.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um, Cat Melvin Bamante told Piers
Morgan he would pretty much be doing the
same thing as Trump if he were
president. Is that reasonable? Like, is
what Trump doing strategic in any sense?
>> Yeah. Bamante also said literally on the
same day in another interview that Trump
was so insane that he and his wife and
kids were leaving the United States
permanently.
So Bamante, the fraud that he is,
just plays to his audience whatever he
thinks they want to hear. He also said
in that interview with Pierce Morgan, he
says, "I'm not trying to stroke you,
Pierce, but your questions are sheer
genius.
Can't stand
our folks 92. Have you met Putin's Have
you read Putin's essay on the
justification for the invasion of
Ukraine? Is it a genuine example of
non-Americans caring more about history
or just retroactive justification for a
lands grab? Well, it's it's certainly
the former. I mean, you know, Putin's a
huge student like all Russians. Russians
care about history. Uh history's front
and present for them. Um and Putin's
definitely an avid history of he wants
to make Russia great again like like
it's he wants to roll like it's 1350 all
over again. Um
>> that is right.
>> Now is that so what's so then uh is it
retroactive justification for a land
grab? Well, it's definitely
justification, right? That's what he's
trying to do.
>> Yes,
>> obviously.
>> Yeah, that's it. It is. Yeah.
>> Um
>> but you're right. You know the
>> Go ahead.
>> Sorry. No, no, we only have a minute
left. You go right ahead.
>> No, go ahead. I was going to say he
understands Russians in general
understand history so much better than
Americans do and they have such a longer
view of issues because they're their
views are are rooted in history. Ours
are not
>> totally. Um and with that, thank you
John very much as always. Hope you enjoy
your weekend and that uh good weekend
everybody stay out of the snow. Um okay
so uh it is it is now 10:00 Eastern
which means it's time for the tmi show
with me and middleach. Please stay tuned
for that. Um, we dropped a DMZ America
podcast yesterday about ICE, which
worked out really well. I highly
recommend that you go check that out.
John and I will be back here doing the
program uh at 9:00 a.m. Eastern time and
all next week on uh 9:00 a.m. Eastern
time throughout the weekdays. So, please
tune in then. Have an awesome weekend.
Thank you very much and see you. See you
later, John.
>> Bye, everybody. Bye, Ted.
>> Bye.